vipbrands.com 2019-03-16

# Privacy and Security

Welcome to the VipBrands website (the "Site"), covering all registered domain endings, such as ".com".   
This privacy policy applies to VipBrands.com owned and operated by Vipbrands Electronic Commerce, a company duly incorporated, organized and registered under the turkish law with registered office at Istanbul - Turkey (hereinafter referred to together with its subsidiaries and affiliates as VipBrands), in its capacity of controller of the personal data.  
you must provide and are responsible for all equipment necessary to access the Site.  
VipBrands.com FZ / DWC (registered address: Business Park, Dubai Aviation City-Logistics City, P.O.BOX: 128984, Dubai - UAE) owns the site.

It is also " VIP MAK GENERAL TRADING LLC " License No. \ 714 469 \ a company incorporated and registered in accordance with the organization and assets under UAE law and headquartered Dubai, United Arab Emirates, operates and manages this site: www.vipbrands.com  
Products will be delivered and invoiced by VIP MAK GENERAL TRADING LLC (address: Alsafa 1, Shikh Zayed Road, Al Matloob building, Office 220, P.O. Box 390082, Dubai, UAE).  
In addition to regional offices in Turkey, Azerbaijan, Russia, Belarus, Ukraine and London. VipBrands keen on the privacy of all users and visitors to the site, where you specify the Privacy Policy in detail how the personal information that users and visitors by providing management of the site.

If you have any suggestions, we are pleased to receive our agents address or e-mail: arabia@vipbrands.com, can also contact us by telephone no +971 4 3214108

## PRIVACY POLICY FOR VIPBRANDS.COM

**1\. DATA THAT WE COLLECT**

We may collect various information if you seek to place an order for a product to us on the Site.

We collect, process your data for processing your purchase on the Site and any possible later claims, and to provide you with our services. We may collect your title, name, gender, email address, postal address, delivery address (if different), telephone number, mobile number, fax number, payment details, payment card details or bank account details.

We will use the information you provide to enable us to process your orders and to provide you with the services and information offered through our website and which you request. Further, we will use the information you provide to administer your account with us; verify and carry out financial transactions in relation to payments you make online; audit the downloading of data from our website; improve the layout and/or content of the pages of our website and customise them for users; identify visitors on our website; carry out research on our users’ demographics; send you information we think you may find useful or which you have requested from us, including information about our products and services, provided you have indicated that you have not objected to being contacted for these purposes. Subject to obtaining your consent we may contact you by email with details of other products and services. If you prefer not to receive any marketing communications from us, you can opt out at any time.

We may pass your name and address on to a third party in order to make delivery of the product to you (for example to our courier or supplier).  
Your phone number may be used for notifications regarding order status and announcements of latest deals and campaigns.

Payments that you make through the Site will be processed by our agent. You must only submit to us or our Agent or the Site information which is accurate and not misleading and you must keep it up to date and inform us of changes.

Your actual order details may be stored with us but for security reasons cannot be retrieved directly by us. However, you may access this information by logging into your account on the Site. Here you can view the details of your orders that have been completed, those which are open and those which are shortly to be dispatched and administer your address details, bank details and any newsletter to which you may have subscribed. You undertake to treat the personal access data confidentially and not make it available to unauthorised third parties. We cannot assume any liability for misuse of passwords unless this misuse is our fault.

**Credit Check and Fraud Prevention**

We may use fraud prevention (FPA) agencies to help us make decisions as to whether to accept an order for products on the Site. A condensed guide as to how we, FPAs will use your information is detailed below. If you would like to see more information about this, or the agencies we use, please contact us. We will use your data in the following ways:

• We will search at FPAs for information on those placing orders for products on the Site.  
• We will use the information provided to us by FPAs to help make decisions about all those placing order for products on the Site.  
• If you give us false or inaccurate information and we identify fraud, details may be passed to FPAs.

**Other uses of your personal information**

We may use your personal information for opinion and market research. Your details are anonymous and will only be used for statistical. You can choose to opt out of this at any time. Any answers to surveys or opinion polls VipBrands may ask you to complete will not be forwarded on to third parties. Disclosing your email address is only necessary if you would like to take part in competitions. We save the answers to our surveys separately from your email address.

We may also send you other information about us, the Site, our other websites, our products, sales promotions, our newsletters, anything relating to other companies in our group or our business partners. If you would prefer not to receive any of this additional information as detailed in this paragraph (or any part of it) please click the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email that we send to you. Within 7 working days (days which are neither (i) a Friday or Saturday, nor (ii) a public holiday anywhere in The United Arab Emirates) of receipt of your instruction, we will cease to send you information as requested. If your instruction is unclear, we will contact you for clarification.

We may further anonymise data about users of the Site generally and use it for various purposes, including ascertaining the general location of the users and usage of certain aspects of the Site or a link contained in an email to those registered to receive them, and supplying that anonymised data to third parties such as publishers. However, that anonymised data will not be capable of identifying you personally.

**Competitions**

For any competition we use the data to notify winners and advertise our offers. You can find more details where applicable in our participation terms for the respective competition.

**Third Parties and Links**

We may share collected personally identifying information (including email addresses) with other companies in our group and for commercial purposes - such as advertising. We may also pass your details to our agents and subcontractors to help us with any of our uses of your data set out in our Privacy Policy. For example, we may use third parties to assist us with delivering products to you, to help us to collect payments from you, to analyse data and to provide us with marketing or customer service assistance. We may exchange information with third parties for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. We may transfer our databases containing your personal information if we sell our business or part of it. Other than as set out in this Privacy Policy, we shall NOT sell or disclose your personal data to third parties without obtaining your prior consent unless this is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy or unless we are required to do so by law. The Site may contain advertising of third parties and links to other sites or frames of other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those third parties or other sites, nor for any third party to whom we transfer your data in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

**Use of Facebook Social Plugins**

Our website uses social plugins (“plugins”) provided by the social network facebook.com, operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). The plugins are identifiable by a Facebook logo or the notice “Facebook Social Plugin”. For a full list of all social plugins and their appearance please see developers.facebook.com/plugins.  
When you visit a page of our website that contains a social plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to Facebook servers. Facebook directly transfers the plugin content to your browser which embeds the latter into the website, enabling Facebook to receive information about your having accessed the respective page of our website. For this purpose, the internet address of the visited site (your IP address included) is transferred to a USA-based Facebook server where the data are stored. This occurs even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not logged into Facebook at the time.  
If you are logged into Facebook, your visit can be assigned to your Facebook account. If you interact with the plugins, for example by clicking “Like”, or entering a comment, the corresponding information is transmitted from your browser directly to Facebook and stored by it. The information can also be published on Facebook, and shown to your Facebook friends.  
If you are a Facebook member and do not want Facebook to connect the data concerning your visit to our website with your member data already stored by Facebook, please log off Facebook before entering our website. You can also block Facebook social Plugins by using add-ons for your browser, like the “Facebook Blocker”.  
For information on the purpose and scope of data collection by Facebook and how it is processed and used, as well as your rights in this respect and settings options for protecting your privacy please visit Facebook’s privacy policy.

**2\. COOKIES**

It is not necessary to accept cookies to visit our website. However, if you would like to place an order or add an item to your shopping basket, you will need to set your browser to accept cookies so you can use the shopping basket and checkout functions.

**What are Cookies?**

Cookies and flash cookies are small files that are saved on your data carrier which store specific information about your preferred settings and any other data that our system needs when interacting with your browser. There are two different kinds of cookies: session cookies, which are deleted the moment you quit your browser; and temporary/permanent cookies, which are stored on your data carrier for a longer period of time or, in some cases, permanently. Cookies help us to tailor our website to suit you and to reflect your tastes and your browsing habits. They also allow us to save any information you have entered so you don’t have to enter it all again the next time you visit.

**What kind of cookies do VipBrands use?**

Most of the cookies we use are session cookies which are deleted at the end of your browser session. We use these to allow you to use our shopping basket function across more than page of our site, for example. We do use some cookies that remain on your computer after you have quit your browser. This kind of cookie enables our system to recognise that you’ve visited our website before and to remember which settings and products you preferred. These temporary/permanent cookies have a lifespan of around one month to two years, after which they will be automatically deleted. These cookies allow us to collect and analyse data to come up with strategies to improve our website. This makes our website easier for our customers to use and helps us to provide you with personal recommendation of products you may like. Our aim is to offer you a fun, easy shopping experience on a website that is tailored to your tastes.

**What kind of information is stored in cookies?**

The cookies used by VipBrands are never used to store any personal information. Therefore our cookies cannot be traced back to an individual user. Once a cookie is activated, it is given an ID number, which is solely used for internal reference and cannot be used to identify the user or access any personal information, such as your name or IP address. The anonymised information we receive from the cookies allows us to assess which pages of our site are visited the most and see which products were most popular etc.

**What is on-site targeting?**

The VipBrands website gathers information that could be useful in tailoring our adverts and online offer to our customers. This information is not used to identify you as a user; it is solely used for the optimization of our website. Information collected by our cookies is not stored with our customer’s personal information or order information, it is only used to provide our users with adverts and/or notification of offers and services that are suited to their individual tastes, using click stream analysis (e.g. adverts for reduced trainers if a customer has been browsing our sports shoe selection). Our goal is to provide you with a shopping experience suited to your tastes and shopping preferences.

**Do VipBrands use third party cookies?**

Cookies from specific business partners are allowed by VipBrands for the purpose of tailoring their adverts to your tastes and browsing habits, so cookies from some of our partners may be stored on your computer when you visit our site. These cookies are temporary/permanent cookies, which will be automatically deleted from your computer at the end of their lifespan (14 days to 2 years). As with our cookies, these third party cookies do not collect any personal information. The data stored is collected at certain times, allowing these companies to see which products have been viewed most frequently but this is done completely anonymously under randomly designated user ID numbers. Therefore, this data will never be pooled with any personal information you have given to VipBrands. Third party cookies have the sole purpose of allowing our partners to advertise products that may interest you.

**Re-targeting**

Our website uses retargeting, which allows us to make our online offer more interesting for you. Retargeting technology means we can advertise recently viewed and related products on our partners’ websites, meaning our adverts, even on other companies’ sites, are relevant to what you would like to see. We do this by analysing user behaviour from data collected by our cookies. Even this kind of information is anonymous, with no personal information being stored and no user profiles.

**Declaration of Consent**

I hereby give permission for my user information to be stored on cookie files. I also allow these files to remain on my computer after I have ended my browser session so they may be used upon my next visit to the website. I reserve the right to retract this permission by changing my browser setting to refuse cookies.

**How can I prevent cookies from being stored on my computer?**

You can change the settings in your browser to ask for your permission every time a cookie tries to access your computer. If you would like to accept VipBrands cookies but block our partners’ cookies, you can set your browser to block third party cookies.

Usually, your browser’s help section will provide information on how to change your cookie settings.

We recommend only changing the browser setting for your profile on shared computers.

The Site uses technology from Webtrekk GmbH (www.webtrekk.de) through which data is collected and stored for marketing and optimisation purposes and data use profiles are prepared under a pseudonym. Cookies may be used for this. The cookies enable recognition of the Internet browser. The data collected with the Webtrekk-technologies is not used, without separate authorisation by the person concerned, to personally identify the visitors to this website and is not collated with personal data on the pseudonym holder. The permission for data recording and storage may at any time be cancelled with on-going effect.  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

**3\. LOG INFORMATION**

Every time you visit VipBrands, information is sent from your browser to our server log files, where it will be saved. The information transferred includes: time and date or visit to our site, which pages were viewed, IP address, URL of site that referred you to VipBrands, how much information has been stored and which browser you have been using.  
Once we have all this information, all IP addresses are deleted or anonymised. Anonymisation means that your IP address is changed in such a way that they either cannot be linked with the original user or can only be linked through extensive research.

The anonymous information stored in this log file is then used to improve the shopping experience on the VipBrands website by making our navigation more user-friendly, finding errors quickly and directing our server’s capacity to where it is needed most. For example, this information allows us to work out our busiest times and plan enough server power for those times to keep our site running as quickly as possible.  
I hereby give my permission for VipBrands to analyse and use protocol data to develop and optimise their online shop.

**4\. SECURITY**

We have in place appropriate technical and security measures to prevent unauthorized or unlawful access to or accidental loss of or destruction or damage to your information. When we collect data through the Site, we collect your personal details on a secure server. We use firewalls on our servers. When we collect payment card details electronically, we use encryption by using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) coding. Whilst we are unable to guarantee 100% security, this makes it hard for a hacker to decrypt your details. You are strongly recommended not to send full credit or debit card details in unencrypted electronic communications with us. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection and disclosure of your information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. You are responsible for protecting against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer.

**5\. CONSENT**

By submitting data to us or our agent or using the Site, you consent to our use of your data in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy to verify your identity.

**6\. YOUR RIGHTS**

If you are concerned about your data you have the right to request access to the personal data which we may hold or process about you. You have the right to require us to correct any inaccuracies in your data free of charge. At any stage you also have the right to ask us to stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes.

Please contact us by mail at arabia@vipbrands.com or call no +971 4 3214108 or Visit VIP MAK GENERAL TRADING LLC (address: Alsafa 1, Shikh Zayed Road, Al Matloob building, Office 220, P.O. Box 390082, Dubai, UAE).
